<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Categories on </title>
    <link>/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Categories on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/categories/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>any efforts are underway to promote data sharing in psychology, however it is currently unclear if the in-principle benefits of data availability are being realized in practice. In a recent study, we found that a mandatory open data policy introduced at the journal Cognition led to a substantial increase in available data, but a considerable portion of this data was not reusable. For data to be reusable, it needs to be clearly structured and well-documented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The attrition of the modern scholarly record</title>
      <link>/blog/attrition-scholarly-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/attrition-scholarly-record/</guid>
      <description>Brief summary An extensive and ongoing attrition of the modern scholarly record is impeding a number of important research activities that support verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis. Recently, we launched the Data Ark initiative – an attempt to retrieve, preserve, and liberate important scientific data. However, most of our data requests were not successful. How can we ensure the longevity and accessibility of important research artifacts?
The Great Library of Alexandria was founded with the lofty ambition to gather and preserve all the world’s knowledge under one roof.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>