<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The attrition of the modern scholarly record</title>
      <link>/blog/attrition-scholarly-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/attrition-scholarly-record/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;brief-summary&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brief summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;An extensive and ongoing attrition of the modern scholarly record is impeding a number of important research activities that support verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis. Recently, we launched the Data Ark initiative – an attempt to retrieve, preserve, and liberate important scientific data. However, most of our data requests were not successful. How can we ensure the longevity and accessibility of important research artifacts?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Great Library of Alexandria was founded with the lofty ambition to gather and preserve all the world’s knowledge under one roof. The Ptolemies of Egypt dispatched their agents to the marketplaces of Athens, Syracuse, and Rhodes in search of valuable papyri. Ships sailing into the bustling port of Alexandria were searched and any books found on board were confiscated&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Eventually, a large collection of influential original works was amassed, covering all manner of subjects from poetry to mathematics, penned by such luminaries as Aristotle and Euripides. And then, torched by fire, jolted by earthquake, and ravaged by warfare, the Great Library crumbled into ruin, and a valuable portion of the scholarly record was lost forever&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:great-library-fig&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/greatLibrary.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The demise of the Great Library of Alexandria.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: The demise of the Great Library of Alexandria.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demise of the Great Library of Alexandria is a cautionary tale: most would lament such a catastrophic loss and wish that it never be repeated. And yet in the modern era, I will contend, an extensive and ongoing attrition of the scholarly record is being widely tolerated. Firstly, let me expand upon what I mean by “the scholarly record”. It is instinctive to view the scholarly record as the collection of written articles through which we communicate our research - the books and research reports lined up on the shelves of libraries and residing in digital archives. But this view is quite superficial – it is as if you are looking down on a rainforest from a helicopter and not appreciating what lies beneath the canopy. A deeper perspective frames the modern scholarly record as a rich ecosystem of research artifacts: articles, study materials, protocols, analysis code, and data (Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:scholarly-record&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;). From this point of view, an article is only a high-level summary: a verbal scaffold that collates, organizes, and describes a mosaic of other research artifacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:scholarly-record&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/scholarly-record.png&#34; alt=&#34;The modern scholarly record as a rich ecosystem of research artifacts: articles, study materials, protocols, analysis code, and data.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: The modern scholarly record as a rich ecosystem of research artifacts: articles, study materials, protocols, analysis code, and data.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viewing the scholarly record as a mere collection of articles makes it easy to overlook that other research artifacts have important roles to play in the scientific endeavour. Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:open-sci-activities&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt; depicts a number of research activities that are either facilitated by or entirely depend upon having access to one or more research artifacts&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. When research artifacts are unavailable, it undermines the efficiency and credibility of the scientific endeavour by disrupting or preventing these important research activities&lt;a href=&#34;#fn4&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. A striking example is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1126/science.aau9619&#34;&gt;recent dire news&lt;/a&gt; that the Reproducibility Project: Cancer Biology has found it necessary to terminate 32 of its 50 target replication attempts due to a lack of methodological information and access to materials from the original studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:open-sci-activities&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/open-sci-activities.png&#34; alt=&#34;An open scholarly record, richly populated with research artifacts, enables a number of important research activties that faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence-synthesis.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: An open scholarly record, richly populated with research artifacts, enables a number of important research activties that faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence-synthesis.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw data is arguably the most foundational artifact in the scholarly record – it is the empirical evidence that substantiates scientific claims. Data enables independent verification through re-analysis, whether that be repeating the original analysis to establish &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/39cfb&#34;&gt;analytic reproducibility&lt;/a&gt;, or running variations of the original analysis to assess &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1745691616658637&#34;&gt;analytic robustness&lt;/a&gt;. Data can also be &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.plos.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005037&#34;&gt;re-analysed in novel ways&lt;/a&gt;, perhaps by other scientists who differ in expertise or theoretical approach, or perhaps by future scientists who have access to some equipment or technique that does not currently exist. Finally, raw data can enable &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.c221&#34;&gt;more sophisticated forms of evidence synthesis&lt;/a&gt; beyond what can be achieved by meta-analysis of aggregated data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extant scientific literature consists of an enormous body of articles reporting findings and making claims, but it is rare to see the research data that substantiates them&lt;a href=&#34;#fn5&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref5&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. After articles have been published, the data files typically exist on temporary life support – only a fragile network of vines beneath the canopy tentatively binds research artifacts to published articles. Over time this ad-hoc system starts to atrophy: hard drives fail, e-mail addresses stop functioning, colleagues who know the whereabouts of the data files move on to new employment, and before long, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2013.11.014&#34;&gt;data is practically no longer retrievable&lt;/a&gt;. Requesting data directly from authors is typically not successful&lt;a href=&#34;#fn6&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref6&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;6&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Other research artifacts suffer a similar fate. For example, in my work I have documented a lack of access to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/fzpcy&#34;&gt;study protocols&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/39CFB&#34;&gt;analysis scripts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1002456&#34;&gt;study materials&lt;/a&gt;. There was no fire, or earthquake, or war to draw our attention to this state of affairs, but it could be that most of the data generated by humanity’s previous scientific ventures have now been irrecoverably lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can be done? Many efforts are underway to increase the preservation and accessibility of research artifacts for future studies. For example, we &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/39cfb&#34;&gt;recently found&lt;/a&gt;, that a mandatory open data policy introduced at the journal &lt;em&gt;Cognition&lt;/em&gt; was highly effective at increasing access to data&lt;a href=&#34;#fn7&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref7&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;7&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But these efforts will not address the fact that data remains unavailable for the majority of the extant published literature. This was the motivation for &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201856&#34;&gt;our recent effort to create the Data Ark&lt;/a&gt;: an open online repository where data retrieved from influential scientific studies could be preserved and liberated for verification and re-use by the research community. Essentially, this was an attempt to reinforce a critical part of the scholarly record and ensure its accessibility and longevity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We began by contacting the authors of 111 of the most highly-cited articles published in psychology and psychiatry between 2006 and 2016, and asked if they would be willing to share the corresponding raw data publicly in the Data Ark. We also provided the option of suggesting that certain access restrictions be put in place, for example in the case of sensitive data. If authors were unwilling to share, we asked for the reason(s) why so we could better understand barriers to data sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:data-ark-fig&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/blog/2018-08-04-attrition-scholarly-record_files/figure-html/data-ark-fig-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Responses to our data sharing request in an effort to populate the Data Ark. You can see a breakdown of responses based on field (psychology vs. psychiatry) and time period (2006-2011 vs. 2014-2016) in the [paper](https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201856).&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Responses to our data sharing request in an effort to populate the Data Ark. You can see a breakdown of responses based on field (psychology vs. psychiatry) and time period (2006-2011 vs. 2014-2016) in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201856&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main findings are shown in Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:data-ark-fig&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;. As you can see, we were only able to retrieve 10 out of the 111 target data sets for unrestricted sharing in the Data Ark (you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/view/DataArk/&#34;&gt;find them here&lt;/a&gt;). Note that in 22 cases data were already being shared via some existing system, but only 5 of these allowed unrestricted access. Of course data sharing is not always straightforward and can be constrained by legal or ethical obligations. We discuss additional findings related to these issues in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201856&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;, such as the access restrictions for existing sharing schemes and the reasons provided by authors who responded that they would not share. However, in the many cases where we received no response, it was impossible to learn about these potential barriers, and for the scientific community to judge if there are appropriate reasons not to share. These data are essentially lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our initial efforts to populate the Data Ark have highlighted just how challenging it can be to retrieve and preserve data from published studies. We had hoped that targeting particularly influential studies would yield a higher success rate than previous efforts. It should be a priority that these data are preserved and liberated to enable independent verification and re-use by the scientific community. It may be that data requests are more likely to be successful in the context of a specific research project and when tangible benefits (e.g., authorship on a paper) for original authors are more obvious. For example, data retrieval seems to have been highly successful in &lt;a href=&#34;https://orca.cf.ac.uk/109813/1/Morey.%20Benchmarks%20for%20model.pdf&#34;&gt;a recent effort to establish an empirical common ground&lt;/a&gt; for the purposes of computational modeling in the domain of short-term and working memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we do not know what substantive scientific projects of the future would bear fruit if only they could be pollinated by the scientific data of today. That is why it is essential to ensure the preservation of important data while we still have the chance to retrieve them. Our findings clearly raise questions about the current norms of data stewardship. As a community we do not deem it appropriate for researchers to grant ethical approval for their own studies - is it not similarly inappropriate for researchers who originally generated data to retain responsibility for their preservation and govern their access? Would journals, data repositories, and/or ethics boards be more reliable and impartial custodians of data?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern scholarly record is not under threat from fire, earthquake, or war, but action is needed to avert the consequences of neglectful stewardship. How many published claims cannot be directly verified because the underlying data that substantiates them are not available? How many new discoveries have we missed because data cannot be re-used in novel analyses? How many replication attempts have been thwarted by a lack of access to original study materials? How many resources have been wasted re-building stimuli and re-writing code that our colleagues have already laboured on? How many misleading findings could have been avoided if pre-registered protocols enabled the research community to identify and challenge ‘behind the scenes’ research decisions? The ongoing attrition of research artifacts has led to a greatly impoverished scholarly record – a desolate landscape of withered vines where flowers could be blooming. An ancient scholar lamenting the demise of the Great Library would look at their modern ancestors, blessed as they are with their God-like technological powers, and wonder how they could possibly tolerate such a situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;rather cheekily, it appears that owners were often reimbursed with copies, whilst the original literary texts were purloined for the Great Library’s collection.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;there is considerable uncertainty about the nature and timeline of events that led to the library’s demise. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.2307/2165947&#34;&gt;Delia (1992)&lt;/a&gt; discusses various accounts.&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;for more details see the “Why share” section of &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.158&#34;&gt;Klein et al. (2018)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;see for example &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1016/%20S0140-6736(13)62296-5&#34;&gt;Chan et al. (2014)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1745691612464056&#34;&gt;Ioannidis (2012)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;see for example &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0024357&#34;&gt;Alsheikh-Ali et al. (2011)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1002333&#34;&gt;Iqbal et al. (2016)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref5&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn6&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;see for example &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.13&#34;&gt;Vanpaemel et al. (2015)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/0003-066X.61.7.726&#34;&gt;Wicherts et al. (2006)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref6&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn7&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1525/collabra.102&#34;&gt;Nuijten et al. (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref7&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open data are not enough</title>
      <link>/blog/open-data-are-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/open-data-are-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;brief-summary&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Brief summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Access to data can enable a number of important research activities that faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis, ultimately leading to a more efficient, progressive, and credible scientific ecosystem. Many efforts are underway to increase the amount of data sharing, however it is currently unclear if the in-principle benefits of data sharing are being realized in practice. In a recent study we found that a mandatory data sahring policy introduced at the journal Cognition led to a substantial increase in available data, but we also found that a considerable portion of this data was unlikely to be reusable by other researchers. For data to be reusable, it needs to be clearly structured and well-documented. Open data alone will not be enough to achieve the benefits envisioned by proponents of data sharing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This blog is co-written with Mike Frank.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology is currently navigating a period of &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177%2F1745691612465253&#34;&gt;crisis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177%2F1745691617751884&#34;&gt;opportunity&lt;/a&gt;. Growing calls for the adoption of &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.158&#34;&gt;transparent&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-016-0021&#34;&gt;reproducible&lt;/a&gt; research practices and starting to elicit a response and a number of journals have begin to introduce new policies to implement change. Data availability is an especially pertinant issue because data access can enable a number of important research activities (see Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:open-data-activities&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;). These include repeating original analyses to recover reported values (analytic reproducibility), employing sensitivity analyses to examine the robustness of outcomes across multiple analysis specifications, conducting novel analyses that make different assumptions or utilise different techniques, and synthesising evidence across multiple studies via meta-analysis. These research activities faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis and should ultimately lead to a more efficient, progressive, and credible scientific ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the extent to which the in-principle benefits of data sharing are being realized in practice is currently unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our assessment is sure to be an underestimate of data probs - as our more in-depth check revealed a number of data-related problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:open-data-activities&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/open-data-activities.png&#34; alt=&#34;Open data can enables a number of research activities that faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Open data can enables a number of research activities that faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2015, I (Tom) was visiting the Center for Open Science and joined a project being led by Mallory Kidwell to evaluate the impact of an ‘open badges’ scheme introduced at the journal Psychological Science. The idea was that authors who voluntarily shared their data and/or research materials would have their paper stamped with a colourful badge, signalling their adoption of open practices to the community. This seems to have been pretty successful; introduction of the badges scheme was associated with an almost 10-fold increase in the proportion of articles reporting available data&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; class=&#34;footnoteRef&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It was great to see so many data sets being shared, but one finding from our paper troubled me: a substantial proportion (50/111, 45%) of reportedly available data was in fact not available, incomplete, incorrect, or had insufficient documentation. This include a few articles that had received open data badges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ideals of data sharing in principle are not yet being realized in practice&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;see these thought-provoking blogs by Hilda Bastian (&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.plos.org/absolutely-maybe/2017/08/29/bias-in-open-science-advocacy-the-case-of-article-badges-for-data-sharing/&#34;&gt;blog1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.plos.org/absolutely-maybe/2017/09/01/whats-open-whats-data-whats-proof-whats-spin/&#34;&gt;blog2&lt;/a&gt;) that suggest considerable caution is needed before making causal claims).&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;submitted-or-under-revision&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Submitted or under revision&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferrero, M., &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Konstantinidis, E., &amp;amp; Vadillo, M. A. (submitted). The efficacy of refutation texts to correct misconceptions among educators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;peer-reviewed-journal-articles&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Peer-reviewed journal articles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Ioannidis, J. P. A. (in press). Mapping the universe of Registered Reports.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Nature Human Behaviour&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/rv7eb/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/uzegq/&#34;&gt;[materials]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/uzfjp/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.24433/CO.03fa2564-3910-4982-9882-4f2fcec50385.v3&#34;&gt;[reproducibleContainer]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/FZPCY&#34;&gt;[preprint]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Mathur, M. B., MacDonald, K., Nilsonne, G., Banks, G. C., Kidwell, M. C., Hofelich Mohr, A., Clayton, E., Yoon, E. J., Henry Tessler, M., Lenne, R. L., Altman, S., Long, B., &amp;amp; Frank, M. C. (in press). Data availability, reusability, and analytic reproducibility: Evaluating the impact of a mandatory open data policy at the journal Cognition.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Royal Society Open Science&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/q4qy3/&#34;&gt;[pre-registration]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/6s8b3/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/k2mdr/&#34;&gt;[materials]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/wf3as/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.24433/CO.abd8b483-c5e3-4382-a493-1fc5aecb0f1d.v2&#34;&gt;[reproducibleContainer]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/39CFB&#34;&gt;[preprint]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Ioannidis, J. P. A. (2018). Populating the Data Ark: An attempt to retrieve, preserve, and liberate data from the most highly-cited psychology and psychiatry articles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PLOS ONE&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0201856&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/Hardwicke_Ioannidis_2018_plos_one.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/r38qu/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/4dum6/&#34;&gt;[materials]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/7syrt/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.24433/CO.241ffbb1-5b81-44bd-94f4-d066b62c5f7f.v2&#34;&gt;[reproducibleContainer]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Henry Tessler, M., Peloquin, B., &amp;amp; Frank, M. C. (2018). A Bayesian decision-making framework for replication.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Behavioral and Brain Sciences&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X18000675&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/N3YAH&#34;&gt;[preprint]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klein, O., &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Aust, F., Breuer, J., Danielsson, H., Hofelich Mohr, A., IJzerman, H., Nilsonne, G., Vanpaemel, W., &amp;amp; Frank, M. C. (2018). A practical guide for transparency in psychological science.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Collabra: Psychology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1525/collabra.158&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/transparencyGuide.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/xf6ug/&#34;&gt;[materials]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristea, I. A., Naudet, F., Shanks, D. R., &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt; (2017). Post-retrieval Tetris should not be likened to a ‘cognitive vaccine’.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Molecular Psychiatry&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/mp.2017.222&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;files/Cristea_tetris_2017.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/nwz9j/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/p3z58/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kidwell, M. C., Lazarević, L. B., Baranski, E., &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Piechowski, S., Falkenberg, L-S., Kennett, C., Slowik, A., Sonnleitner, C., Hess-Holden, C., Errington, T. M., Fiedler, S., &amp;amp; Nosek, B. A. (2016). Badges to acknowledge open practices: A simple, low cost, effective method for increasing transparency.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PLOS Biology&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1002456&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/openBadges.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/3upzh/&#34;&gt;[pre-registration]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/u6g7t/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/8kt4b/&#34;&gt;[materials]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/257kv/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Shanks, D. R. (2016). Reply to Walker and Stickgold: Proposed boundary conditions on memory reconsolidation will require empirical verification.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1608235113&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/sequenceReconReply.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Mahdi, T., &amp;amp; Shanks, D. R. (2016). Post-retrieval new learning does not reliably induce human memory updating via reconsolidation.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PNAS&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1601440113&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/sequenceRecon.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/bm47u/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/xyf34/&#34;&gt;[materials]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/se6gb/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vadillo, M. A., &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Shanks, D. R. (2016). Selection bias, vote counting, and money priming effects: A comment on Rohrer, Pashler, and Harris (2015) and Vohs (2015).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: General&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.1037/xge0000157&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/moneyPriming.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/4e3gy/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baker, R., Dexter, M., &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Goldstone, A., &amp;amp; Kourtzi, Z. (2014). Learning to predict: Exposure to temporal sequences facilitates prediction of future events.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Vision Research&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.visres.2013.10.017&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/learningToPredict.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ludwig, C. J. H., Farrell, S., Ellis, L. A., &lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Gilchrist, I. D. (2012). Context-gated statistical learning and its role in visual-saccadic decisions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Journal of Experimental Psychology: General&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0024916&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/contextGatedSL.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;other-publications&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other publications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt; (2016). Persistence and plasticity in the human memory system: An empirical investigation of the overwriting hypothesis.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PhD Thesis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dx.doi.org/10.17605/OSF.IO/R4C32&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/Hardwicke_thesis.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/rxtgs/&#34;&gt;[data]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/rxtgs/&#34;&gt;[analysisCode]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/rxtgs/&#34;&gt;[osf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt;, Jameel, L., Jones, M., Walczak, E. J., &amp;amp; Magis-Weinberg, L. (2014). Only human: Scientists, systems, and suspect statistics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Opticon1826&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.5334/opt.ch&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/files/onlyHuman.pdf&#34;&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardwicke, T. E.&lt;/strong&gt; (2012). Biological Psychology.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Psychology Learning &amp;amp; Teaching&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.2304/plat.2012.11.1.106&#34;&gt;[doi]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
