<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The attrition of the modern scholarly record</title>
      <link>/blog/attrition-scholarly-record/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/attrition-scholarly-record/</guid>
      <description>Brief summary An extensive and ongoing attrition of the modern scholarly record is impeding a number of important research activities that support verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis. Recently, we launched the Data Ark initiative – an attempt to retrieve, preserve, and liberate important scientific data. However, most of our data requests were not successful. How can we ensure the longevity and accessibility of important research artifacts?
The Great Library of Alexandria was founded with the lofty ambition to gather and preserve all the world’s knowledge under one roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are open data actually reusable?</title>
      <link>/blog/open-data-are-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/open-data-are-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>Brief summary Access to data can enable a number of important research activities that faciliate verification, discovery, and evidence synthesis, ultimately leading to a more efficient, progressive, and credible scientific ecosystem. Many efforts are underway to increase the amount of data sharing, however it is currently unclear if the in-principle benefits of data sharing are being realized in practice. In a recent study we found that a mandatory data sharing policy introduced at the journal Cognition led to a substantial increase in available data, but a considerable portion of this data was not reusable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>